WILLIAM DIEP

Software Developer specializing in front end development with an appreciation and eye for modern clean designs. Experience in full development cycle (design, development, and deployment)

Background includes seven years of experience in systems administration and tech support, and ten years of experience in teaching and mentoring. Recent positions include providing customer-centric tier 1 and 2 support with scopes of project management and consulting services. Passion for contributing to open source, learning new technologies, and teaching

- WillWebDesigns@gmail.com
- www.williamdiep.me
- **♀** SF Bay Area, CA
- in www.linkedin.com/in/wdiep

Skills

HTML5/CSS3

SASS

JavaScript/ES6

Reactis

iQuery

AJAX

Templating Engines

Webpack

GulpJS

Bootstrap 4

Foundation 6

Git

Wordpress

MVC Architecture

BEM Methodology

Content Management Systems

Responsive Web Design

Responsive HTML Emails

Search Engine Optimization

Web Accessibility

Google Analytics

MailChimp

Adobe Photoshop

NodeJS

Express

NoSQL (MongoDB)

Linux

Digital Ocean

Amazon Web Services

Nginx

Apache

Experience

Will's Web Designs

Full Stack Developer (Front End Focus)

Portfolio: https://www.williamdiep.me

- · Design, develop, and deploy full stack responsive web apps and websites for startups and small businesses
- · Services include best practices of SEO and web accessibility, Google Analytics, and responsive HTML newsletters
- Consult with clients, provide scope of projects, proposals, and statement of work

theCoderSchool

Coding Instructor

San Jose & Fremont, CA · Jul 2017

SF Bay Area, CA \cdot May 2016 to Current

 Instruct and mentor 6 - 16 year olds web development, game development, and data structures and algorithms using HTML5/ CSS3, JavaScript, and Python

NASA Ames Research Center

Mountain View, CA · Jul 2013 to Oct 2013

Web Content Developer (Intern)

https://science.nasa.gov/earth-science

- Created, revised, and managed webpages for the Earth Science Division using HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript.
 Improved web usability and web accessibility while providing administrative support to senior team members
- Collaboratively worked in a team of four to effectively create over 25 high-quality designs of brochures, posters, and presentations using Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Photoshop in an aggressive one-month timeframe resulting an increase of \$28K funding
- Coached three interns on a 1-1 basis on web design/development, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, & Microsoft Office Suite increasing team efficiency by ten fold

GoFundMe

Redwood City, CA · Aug 2016 to Nov 2016

IT Administrator (Contract)

 Sole technician who provided technical support and systems administration to 100+ users in new office supporting executives, finance, marketing, and engineering departments

DominoComp Technology Source

San Jose, CA · Sep 2014 to Jan 2016

IT Support Specialist

- Provided tier 1 and 2 software and hardware support locally and remotely to 100+ clients
- Reduced help desk calls by 30% by developing end-user training and knowledge database

Citi's Sleepworld

San Jose, CA · Jun 2011 to Sep 2014

IT & Customer Services Support

- Provided desktop support and trained 25 staffs the efficiently use of business systems and peripherals improving weekly shipments by double
- · Handled customer inquiries, billing concerns, service requests, and issued return merchandise authorizations

Foothill-De Anza Community College District

Cupertino, CA · Aug 2009 to Jun 2011

IT Support Assistant

Education

San Jose State University

Bachelor of Science Health Science 2013 GPA 3.4/4.0

Foothill College

Associate of Science Computer Science 2018 GPA 3.85/4.0

Front End Developer Code Camp (Cañada College)

2016

Enrolled in a 16-week immersive training program learning front-end programming, data structures, algorithms, & agile development. Collaborated in agile teams to plan and create websites and web apps